### Ariana Nesbit

Full Stack Software Engineer

(571) 242.4758 · ariananesbit@gmail.com · Aurora, CO · in/ariananesbit · github.com/nesbita

I am a full stack software engineer who wants to create applications that make a positive difference in the world. I am diligent and detail oriented, and easily build rapport with others. I have four years of critical care experience which has taught me to think quickly on my feet and to be flexible. I'm interested in projects that will impact the environment, animals, and those who are less fortunate than myself. I'm looking forward to growing as a developer and learning all that I can.

### **SKILLS**

Languages - HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript | Libraries and Frameworks - React, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Material-UI, Styled-Components, Bootstrap, Flask

Database - PostgreSQL, Sequelize, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM, SQLAlchemy | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON, APIs

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

May 2021 - Present

# Falendar | Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, RESTful Routing, React, CSS

- A MERN stack application created with a group over a week to allow families to better coordinate their schedules via calendar
- Added functionality with RESTful routing for CRUD operations and tested back-end routes with Postman
- Used Mongoose to interact with MongoDB database
- Styled with CSS in React, Styled-Components, and Material-UI

## Market Match | Express, Node.js, RESTful Routing, Sequelize, EJS

- A full stack Express and Postgres application created over one week to allow users to locate their closest farmers market using the USDA National Farmers Market Directory API
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all back-end routes during development using Postman.
- Used ORM Sequelize to interact with database
- Styled with Express server utilizing EJS/EJS layouts

#### Nature Walk | HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- A front-end game in which users go through a slideshow and encounter different scenarios and outcomes
- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for game development, formatting, and display

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Denver Health, Healthcare Technician III | Denver, CO

Jan 2017 - Present

- Monitor up to 24 critically ill patients per day in the Medical Intensive Care Unit, ensuring patient safety and best outcomes
- Promoted from healthcare tech I to healthcare tech III based on skills mastery, recognition from coworkers, and diligence
- Perform EKGs, set up 5 lead EEGs, specimen collection
- Maintain patient records and privacy via EMR (Epic), maintain unit records, and carry out administrative tasks
- Received multiple Heroes of the Heart and Compassionate Care Awards in addition to receiving a Daisy Award nomination and frequent written recognition

#### Castle Country Assisted Living, Qualified Medication Administration Personnel (QMAP) | Parker, CO Oct 2013 - Oct 2017

- Quickly and accurately identified, prepared, administered, monitored, and ordered medications (including controlled substances) for 26 residents at an assisted living facility
- Verified and transcribed doctors' orders in Medication Administration Record (MAR)
- Maintained and updated MAR to ensure safety of residents and to ensure proper documentation of myself and others
- Led daily activities and enrichment for 16-26 residents to promote engagement

### **EDUCATION**

# GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

May 2021 - July 2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

## UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO DENVER | DENVER, CO

Bachelor of Science in Biology

2017

Pre-med designation, member of Pre-Health Club, Phi Theta Kappa member prior to transfer